Parsa Khayatzadeh | Resume

Systems Engineering Ph.D. student @ Cornell

Ph.D. Student: Systems Engineering, Cornell University

Supervisior:: Prof. Michael Charles

Research Area: Computational Sustainability Techs: IAMs, Human-Earth Systems, Julia, R Ithaca, NY

mr.schochastics.net pk525@cornell.edu

Summary

I have started my Ph.D. at Cornell as a Systems Engineering student under the supervision of Prof. Michael Charles. I am interested in design aspect of human-earth models. I link different modules of the system to provide a narrative of plausible futures of the world. My current research focuses on the downscaled study of IAMs aimed to serve tribal governed communities and my case study is Navajo Nation.

Education

Ph.D. in Systems Engineering - Ithaca, NY

Aug. 2023 - Current

* Area: Computational Sustainability

B.Sc. in Industrial Engineering - Tehran, Iran

Aug. 2018 - Jul. 2022

- * Thesis: PV vs. CSP: a solar renewable technology review and electricity cost analysis based on improvised LCOE
- * Course Highlights: Operations Research System Analysis Engineering Statistics Fundamentals of Probability Microeconomic Theory Macroeconomics Statistical Quality Control Decision Analysis

Experience

Teaching Assistant - GESIS - Leibniz Institute for the Social Sciences

Mar. 2022 - Present

- * Coordination of a project to build an Open Science platform with reusable code and tutorials
- * Research on Open Science Practices
- * Implementation of tools to enhance reproducibility and facilitate research with digital data in R

Presidential Fellow - University of Manchester

Sep. 2018 - Feb. 2022

- * Research on Disinformation on Social Media
- * Analyses of large scale and unstructured data sets with R, Python and Bash

Post Doctoral Researcher - ETH Zurich

Nov. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- * Developing new methods to analyze social networks
- * Implementing methods in libraries
- * Gathering and analyzing large datsets from Social Media APIs

Post Doctoral Researcher - University of Konstanz

Oct. 2015 - Oct. 2017

- * Developing new methods to analyze social networks
- * Implementing methods in libraries
- * Webscraping and harmonizing a large corpus of football data

Ph.D. Candidate - University of Konstanz

Nov. 2012 - Sep. 2015

- * Developing new methods to analyze social networks
- * Implementing methods in libraries